Creating or developing the project
management plan.
So we've gone from initiating where we
developed the project charter.
Now we're moving across that process map
or process matrix.
Remember page 25 in your pinback to
develop the project management plan.
All right.
So the project management
plan is a detailed
document defining
the basis of all the work.
It will be signed off on.
by your sponsor, the PM, key stakeholders,
key members of the team.
And it will create a baseline for the
entire project.
So we will have all our plan components.
That's what I was telling you before.
The subsidiary plans, pieces of our
puzzle, plus scope, schedule, cost
baselines, which make up altogether the
performance measurement
baseline for your project.
So that's what your plan is made up of.
The subsidiary plans are baselines and
additional documents.
So remember change management plans,
configuration management plans are created
in the very beginning as we develop the
project management plan.
We'll also create a requirements
management plan.
We'll talk about some of the others coming
up.
So throughout the PIMbox 6th edition,
project documents are referred to as ITTOs.
we already discussed those inputs tools
and techniques and outputs remember your
inputs and your outputs or nouns those are
artifacts tools and techniques are things
we'll do and use all right so the
subsidiary management plans pieces of our
puzzle every plan including all the pieces
of the puzzle will address how the work
will be planned executed monitor and
control controlled and how we'll close.
Subsidiary plans consist of scope and
requirements.
Those are done when we plan scope
management.
Schedule, cost, quality, resources,
communications, risk, procurement,
and stakeholder management plans.
We go through the rest of our knowledge
areas, but not just from top to bottom.
We plan, plan, plan, plan, plan.
Some of the first components, pieces of
our puzzle.
Communications and stakeholder
engagement are unbelievably
intertwined, and I will cover
those later, along with risks.
Some of those plans are done early in the
very beginning.
Then we keep planning going through our
planning processes.
All right, additional components.
So parts of our plan, pieces
of our puzzle, change in
configuration management
done in the very beginning.
Remember how changes will be made.
Our stakeholders need to know that.
And then configuration management.
What is being documented, detailed?
How do we keep up with the latest
documents, plans, baselines, versions,
version control.
That's what I want you to think of the
most with configuration management.
The performance measurement baseline will
include our three baselines over here.
Scope is always the first baseline that
has to be created.
The scope has to be agreed
upon before we can figure out
how long it's going to take
and how much it's going to cost.
So our other baselines.
So the performance measurement baseline is
including all three together.
Our project lifecycle, how we're going to
take our project from beginning to end,
our development approach, strategy,
management reviews, project implementation
plan, compliance management plan and then
agile management plans baselining the
project management plan so the project
plan is considered baselined when
appropriate stakeholders have signed off
on our project management plan it again
includes our baselines so appropriate
means our sponsor other key stakeholders
you the project team the baseline is our
starting point where the work of the
project will be executed according to the
baseline our plan actual results will be
compared to the baseline so remember all
of our monitoring and controlling
processes everything below us remember
we're up in integration overseeing
everything we'll compare the plan what was
agreed upon to data what's actually
happening all right so actual results are
compared to the baseline subsequent
changes must go through perform integrated
change control process which i talked
about earlier project may be re-baselined
after sign off from appropriate
stakeholders so if adding or deleting
scope for example example will affect a
baseline the sponsor or CCB change control
board has to authorize that then through
the approved change request we update
plans and documents accordingly so
remember that's a trio discuss that
earlier